<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeklies on PingCAP Site</title>
    <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeklies on PingCAP Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pingcap.com/weekly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 17 ~ September 23, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-25-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-25-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 29 PRs in the TiDB repository.
Added  Support dumping statistics for partitioned tables Add a variable to control the statement priority of a TiDB server Add a WithRecovery() function in the util package  Improved  Remove the DDL version in metrics Set TiDBMemQuotaQuery to the value in the configuration file Prune columns for LogicalTableDual Optimize the IsPoint() function for performance Support limit/group-by/order-by clauses in Point_Get Reuse chunks to reduce memory usage in UnionScan Add correctness check for some system variables Optimize constant fold for null parameter expressions to simplify the outer join Enhance predicate pushdown over join Support the init_vector argument for the built-in function AES_ENCRYPT/AES_DECRYPT  Fixed  Fix a bug in the Format() function for some expressions Fix the session time in show processlist Fix INFORMATION_SCHEMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 10 ~ September 16, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-17-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-17-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 35 PRs in the TiDB repository.
Added  Add a design document for TiDB cluster&amp;rsquo;s system timezone Support resigning the DDL owner and use the ddl/owner/resign HTTP method Write system timezone into the MYSQL.TIDB table in the bootstrap stage Add two built-in functions decode and encode Add a proposal document for a Volcano/Cascades model based SQL planner  Improved  Make the decimal default precision visible in SHOW CREATE TABLE Use the pumps client to write binlog files Improve the error message of GC life time Fill the data length fields for INFORMATION_SCHEMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 03 ~ September 09, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-10-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-10-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 39 PRs in the TiDB repository.
Added  Add different labels for restricted SQL and general SQL metrics Add the USR1 signal handler to dump goroutine Use the point get plan for the UPDATE statement Support load data with IgnoreLines Support the json_contains builtin function  Improved  Make Analyze Buckets number configurable Set HIGH_PRIORITY for the bootstrap SQL statements Only check the range typed partition when creating a partitioned table Make a tiny refactor in the reorganization stage of adding indices Relax the tso backoff limit Reduce chunk&amp;rsquo;s iterator function call Improve compatibility for the MariaDB client Do AutoAnalyze on a certain period of a day Change the logic of converting the logical join to the index join Read the inner table and build hash table parallel in hash join Add batch copy to the inner join and the left and right outer join Add a ctxPool field to the worker struct to make executing the SQL statement in the DDL package possible  Fixed  Fix some datetime related cases which are inconsistent with MySQL Fix a compatibility problem of analyzing period variables Fix an error in the parser when parsing a single line comment ended with a newline character Fix an issue that the gc_delete_range table is queried with a wrong form of timestamp Fix an issue that the bit type can use null as its default value Return the correct column name and column label name Fix a panic when logging detailed statistics Fix a wrong count output of explain for the TableScan plan Fix the update join result when the join table order is changed Fix the issue that creating a partitioned table with bigint columns fails  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we released a new version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 27 ~ September 02, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-03-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-09-03-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 45 PRs in the TiDB repository.
Added  Enable the Mutex profiling in the TiDB server Let Analyze use the RC level and the low priority Support Grow of the chunk capacity Add job action and schema version information to metrics Forbid users to drop an important system table Support rollback when adding an index in a partitioned table Add a KeyOnly option for the Seek operation Maintain HistColl in StatsInfo of DataSource Add a TiDB tracing prototype  Improved  Remove goroutine_pool Remove the test coverage task from travis Rebase the auto increment ID when needed Fix the lint tool Make the duplicate error output in the Update statement more clearly Bump Go version to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 20 ~ August 26, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-27-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-27-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 34 PRs in the TiDB repository.
Added  Make the query feedback work for the partitioned table Support a new aggregate framework for HashAggExec  Fixed  Fix a bug when using a correlated column as the index Fix the prepare result for zero timestamp/time/datetime Fix the Enum type flag bug Make partition by range value accept the constant expression Fix concat in the GROUP statement Fix selecting null value for table partition Use the unified infoschema in select .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 13 ~ August 19, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-20-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-20-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 46 PRs in the TiDB repository.
Added  Store the TiDB server information to PD and add the HTTP API handle Support dropping the index for the partitioned table Support the Replace operation for table partition Add BatchPut and BatchDelete for the Raw client Support CharsetOpt to load the data statement in Parser  Fixed  Fix group_concat when the chunk size is set to 1 Fix the admin check index panic when the index contains the pkIsHandle column Fix the fraction part handle of current_timestamp Fix the panic in checkRangePartitioningKeysConstraints when creating table partitions by range columns Set the proper customized timezone Set the types of index columns in CheckIndexRangeExec Fix the missing microsecond for the timestamp Fix duplicate row check when the chunk size is small Fix the return value of resultType/flag in the enum/set column information  Improved  Log detailed statistics for the query feedback Collect execution details and output them in the slow query log Notify the statistics worker when truncating tables Add a new interface MergePartialResult for the new aggregation framework  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 2 PRs in the TiSpark repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 06 ~ August 12, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-13-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-13-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 46 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the Update operation for table partition Support the prefix index in admin check table  Fixed  Fix behaviors of builtin LTrim, RTrim and Trim Fix group_concat(a) when a is null Make USE INDEX(PRIMARY) work on the integer primary key Fix admin check table false alarm when the index contains the pkIsHandle column Fix inconsistent row count estimation Fix a bug when applying the RenameTable diff  Improved  Perform the batch check for the constrains when adding a unique index Remove Exists in plan and executor Disable the Read Committed isolation level Refactor joinResultGenerator to handle the unmatched outer records Adjust the way of checking all the schema versions Update the import path from coreos/gofail to etcd-io/gofail to fix CI  Weekly update in TiKV and PD Last week, we landed 27 PRs in the TiKV and PD repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 30 ~ August 05, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-06-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-08-06-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 68 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the Delete operation for table partition Support analyzing the partition table  Fixed  Fix the union result when mixing signed and unsigned columns Add BatchPut for RawKV Fix a bug about wrong copying in index join Fix a panic caused by the local feedback Fix a bug in decimal multiplication Sort user records in the privilege cache Fix TruncateTo Fix a bug of update with an outer join Fix admin cleanup index for non-unique handles in a unique index Fix a bug when eliminating a projection Skip inner rows when the join keys contain NULL  Improved  Support fast path point select Always choose the smaller child as the outer table for IndexJoin Remove FromID from expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 23 ~ July 29, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-30-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-30-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 43 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the sum_decimal method for AggFunc Support truncating and dropping partitioned tables Implement the reorganization of table partition when adding the index  Fixed  Fix a bug that the bit and year column types are not supported when a partition table is created Fix a bug in the decimal modulo operation Refactor the code of building Insert Fix a panic caused by the outdated feedback Fix a panic that is upgraded from the old version TiDB Fix a bug that null values cannot be found using the unique index  Improved  Add the partition function check when creating a partition table Provide preliminary support for the parallel DDL operation Use feedback timely Optimize DecodeRowKey Remove the types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 16 ~ July 22, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-23-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-23-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 41 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support group_concat in the new aggregation evaluation framework Support the remained types (String/Time/Duration/JSON) for Max/Min Support FIRST_ROW in the new aggregation evaluation framework Support the admin check table statement for table partition Add the proposal template Add the new storage row format proposal Add the design document about the new aggregate framework Set the PB field type and the ExtraHandle column type  Fixed  Fix the daylight saving time issue Fix the panic of creating partition tables Fix the bug in loading data Fix the OOM issue in the batch operations Add keepalive Truncate the prefix index from runes when the charset is UTF-8 Check b.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 09 ~ July 15, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-16-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-16-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 30 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support BIT_AND/BIT_XOR in the new aggregation framework Support COUNT in the new aggregation framework Support AVG(DISTINCT) in the new aggregation framework Add the GENERATION_EXPRESSION column in information_schema.columns Support more syntactic rules regarding the SET syntax Support ADMIN SHOW DDL JOBS &amp;lt;NUMBER&amp;gt; to specify the lines of the results Support showing AUTO_INCREMENT in information_schema.tables  Fixed  Fix a bug in INSERT SELECT FROM ON DUPLICATE KEY UPDATE Fix the numeric type overflow in the binary protocol Fix the results of decimal Minus/Round/Mul  Improved  Check the schema when the DDL fails Refine the explain result format Speed up autoAnalyze when data is unchanged  Weekly update in TiKV and PD Last week, we landed 19 PRs in the TiKV and PD repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 02 ~ July 08, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-09-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-09-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 34 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support session variables warning_count and error_count Support BIT_OR in the new aggregation function framework  Fixed  Fix the privilege bug when reusing chunks Fix the issue that the Hash Aggregate operator cannot exit Fix a panic on Stream Aggregate Fix the results of SHOW CREATE TABLE when adding indices Fix the results of non-integer inputs for bit related aggregate functions  Improved  Use feedback to refine updating statistics information Refactor statistics updating mechanism to speed up analyzing tables Allow the user to kill his own connections without the SUPER privilege  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 5 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 25 ~ July 01, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-02-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-07-02-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 39 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add a session variable tidb_ddl_reorg_worker_cnt to control the number of the DDL organization workers Support parallel HASH aggregation and greatly improve the performance of the aggregation function Print explain results in a tree style Support the SHOW ERRORS statement and improve the SHOW WARNINGS statement  Fixed  Make the INSERT IGNORE statement ignore BadNullError Fix a bug when only_full_group_by is set in SQL_MODE Fix the wrong results of avg(double) Make the CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS LIKE statement work again Set the correct startHandle when some errors occur in adding indexes Fix a bug in pushing down TopN Fix the response result bug of COM_FIELD_LIST Fix a bug of the str_to_date() function Fix a bug of the INSERT statement when the field type is unsigned float/double  Improved  Use the average error of the row count which is estimated by statistics to determine the pseudo column Use CorrelatedColumn to calculate range Make the frequency of updating the statistic metadata depend on the table size Refactor the execution framework of the aggregate functions Speed up the CreateTable operation Stop calling expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 18 ~ June 24, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-25-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-25-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 18 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the binary fetch command Add a variable to disable auto-retry of the transaction block  Fixed  Allow comments to end up with multiple asterisks as MySQL does  Improved  Allow using IndexJoin in more scenarios Improve the performance of the insert ignore on duplicate key update statement Optimize the accuracy of index row count estimation  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 5 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 11 ~ June 17, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-19-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-19-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 26 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the MySQL syntax show privileges Add the limit for the number of columns when adding columns Add the sanity check of the precision and the scale for numeric types  Fixed  Fix the wrong results of the CONCAT_WS built-in function Fix a bug in right join when some predicates are pushed to the right table Fix the missing start timestamp for TableDual in a transaction  Improved  Refactor the structure of the DDL package Remove new lines and add the user information in the query log Make the limitation of query memory usage configurable Change the factor of the descending scan according to the improvement of descending scan performance in TiKV  Weekly update in TiKV and PD Last week, we landed 28 PRs in the TiKV and PD repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 04 ~ June 10, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-11-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-11-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 50 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support ALTER TABLE RENAME KEY Support SHOW MASTER STATUS Support setting TSO into the tidb_snapshot session variable Support the ALTER TABLE DROP COLUMN CASCADE syntax  Fixed  Make TIDB_SMJ take effect when no index can be used Fix the SelectLock option for the UNION statement Fix a bug of the DROP USER statement Fix a bug of WrapWithCastAsJSON Detect the duplication of table alias for the JOIN statement Fix some bugs of the DECIMAL values Do not allow the YEAR type to have the UNSIGNED flag Refine row count estimation Fix a bug of failing to fetch the profile by pprof Fix the wrong result of the UNION statement Fix the wrong result of Merge Join Handle NULL datum when converting it to a string in statistics Fix the issue of checking LIMIT and ORDER BY in the UNION statement  Improved  Add max backoff settings for tikv-client Support parallel projection Make the error message of ADMIN CHECK TABLE more readable Improve the constant folding for the IF and IFNULL built-in functions Push the FLOOR built-in function to TiKV Push the built-in functions IS TRUE/IS FALSE to TiKV Append the current time into the error message when backoff occurs Refine the result of the EXPLAIN statement  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 2 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 28 ~ June 03, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-04-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-06-04-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 50 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the Trace syntax Support the TIDB_IS_DDL_OWNER builtin function  Support ALL for builtin aggregate function BIT_AND/BIT_OR/BIT_XOR  Fixed  Check the correctness of decimal&amp;rsquo;s exponent part Fix the affected row count for the UPDATE statement Fix the range construction for the IN builtin function Fix the empty result of the JOIN statement Fix row count estimation for the LIMIT operator Fix the error message of the DIV builtin function Check the schema name of the column for the CREATE TABLE statement Fix the side effect of casting one decimal to another decimal  Improved  Push ABS to TiKV Wait for a while when some errors occurred to avoid retrying the DDL job too many times Unify the log format of the connection ID Ignore foreign keys in the SHOW CREATE TABLE statement Change statistics delta update duration to 1 minute Check invalid tasks after physical optimization Unify the DDL logs  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 2 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 21 ~ May 27, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-28-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-28-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 44 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Make tidb_max_chunk_size a global variable Add a timeout for writing binlogs Support high_priority for DELETE/UPDATE/REPLACE INTO statements Support changing the log level online Support ComChangeUser Support JOIN hint for UPDATE/DELETE statements  Fixed  Fix the compatibility problem of ON UPDATE CURRENT_TIMESTAMP Fix a bug of ON DUPLICATE KEY UPDATE Fix the decimal fraction of DIV Fix count estimation of betweenRowCount Fix the wrong result of CEIL(DECIMAL) Fix the wrong result of CEIL(INT) integer Fix the cost estimation of Index Scan and Table Scan Fix a bug of deleting an index in YEAR type Fix the wrong result of FLOOR Fix the false alarm of ADMIN CHECK TABLE Fix a panic of MAX/MIN Fix a bug in rebuildRange when the plan cache for the PREPARE statement is enabled  Improved  Create a new backoff for each Region Do not log the Write error during handshake Refine the log level of stats Set the rollback log to the debug level Refine the comparison between the timestamp column and the string constant Push CEIL down to TiKV  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 2 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 14 ~ May 20, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-21-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-21-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 40 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support TIME and TIMESTAMP binary types for the PREPARE/EXECUTE statements Make tidb_build_stats_concurrency a global variable Support USE INDEX in the DELETE FROM statement  Fixed  Fix the compatibility problem of the UNION statement Fix range calculation of Index Scan when Prepared Plan Cache is enabled Check the AUTO_INCREMENT column for the SHARD_ROW_ID_BITS statement Set PB code for builtinArithmeticDivideDecimalSig  Improved  Refine the error message about Invalid default value Make the error log for WriteConflict more friendly  Add the schema version to the log Support warnings when using Coprocessor streaming Add the DDL Callback log Do not log handshake error Log slow processing and waiting Coprocessor tasks separately with different labels Do not bind graceful shutdown to SIGTERM  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 4 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 07 ~ May 13, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-14-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-14-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 55 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support renaming a table as its original name Allow correlated columns to be pushed down to TiKV Support local latches for the transactions in TiDB Add an option to stop writing Binlog when TiDB meets some Binlog errors Add an HTTP API to enable or disable the general log of TiDB Update the logrus package to a new version  Fixed  Set lastInsertID in the duplicated update statement Fix several bugs of statistics feedback Fix a bug occurred when values are inserted into a time column Fix a bug when creating a table and renaming a table run concurrently Rollback all keys when Prewrite fails Fix a bug when adding index meets handle = MaxInt64 Fix a bug when the limit offset is a multiple of MaxChunkSize Fix a bug when a complex subquery exists in the Update statement  Improved  Refine the error message about Out of range value for column Set gc_worker and loadDeleteRangeSQL to a much higher priority Make tidb_opt_insubquery_unfold a global variable Uniform the calculation method of pseudo statistics Improve the CPU usage when opentracing is not enabled  Weekly update in TiKV and PD Last week, we landed 24 PRs in the TiKV and PD repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 30 ~ May 06, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-07-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-07-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 24 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add DB_NAME and TABLE_NAME in the result of ADMIN SHOW DDL JOBS Add an HTTP API to scatter Regions of a table Add the tidb_retry_limit session variable to control the transaction retry limit Add the auto_analyze_ratio session variable to control the automatic analysis ratio Support the ALTER TABLE FORCE syntax  Fixed  Restrict the column type in range partition Check the privilege for SHOW CREATE TABLE and information_schema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 23 ~ April 29, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-02-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-05-02-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 49 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the CHANGELOG.md file to the TiDB repository Support more ODBC syntaxes Support PARTITION BY RANGE COLUMNS in SHOW CREATE TABLE Support the ALTER CONVERT TO syntax Support the ALTER TABLE AUTO_INCREMENT syntax Support the SET NAMES COLLATE DEFAULT syntax  Fixed  Fix Dump/Load statistics information Fix data race on the LockKeys() function Fix range calculating in the TableHandlesToKVRanges() function Fix the compatibility problem of the UNION statement Fix the wrong behavior of the tryToGetMemTask() function Refine the optimization rule of &amp;ldquo;TopN Push Down&amp;rdquo;  Improved  Add more log information about slow queries Log the slow Coprocessor task in detail Enhance the validation of column names when creating a table  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we released TiSpark 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 16 ~ April 22, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-23-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-23-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 36 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add TiDB HTTP API to query the DDL history information Add the session variable tidb_optimizer_selectivity_level to control the selectivity estimation level Add table partition information in SHOW CREATE TABLE Analyze the table automatically when the modified row count of a table is too large  Fixed  Check if the column name already exists before renaming a column Fix a problem when parallel executing CREATE TABLE IF NOT EXISTS Fix pseudo selectivity estimation for the primary key Eliminate Projection when the schema length is 0 Set the hash join concurrency in NewSessionVars  Improved  Refactor scalarFuncToPBExpr Improve the cost estimation for physical aggregate operators Improve the execution performance of the UnionScanExec operator Cache global variables  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 8 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 09 ~ April 15, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-16-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-16-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 32 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Update the average column size dynamically Update statistics using query feedback Use tidb_index_lookup_join_currency to control the number of IndexLookupJoin inner workers Add a TiDB system variable tidb_hash_join_concurrency Make pseudo estimate ratio configurable Show memory usage in show processlist  Fixed  Make inferring of decimal for unix_timestamp more consistent with MySQL Fix the bug of writing null value into not null column in write-only state Fix the IndexLookUpJoin hang problem Update the column&amp;rsquo;s offset when modifying the column Support insert ignore on duplicate update  Improved  Set explicit_defaults_for_timestamp = on for compatibility with MySQL Increase the default lease Improve the performance of Clone Use a cloned Expression when setting it to plan  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 3 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 02 ~ April 08, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-09-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-09-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 28 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support AdminCleanupIndex to clean up the dangling index Support AlterTableComment Add RawDeleteRange API Make session transaction isolation level take effect only once  Fixed  Fix row estimation for the pseudo unique key Fix row count estimation for the column with null values Fix the result of cast (0x10 as binary(2)) Fix zero value issue for binary type Merge BatchGet results to fix InsertIgnore in a transaction block  Improved  Track memory usage for NestedLoopApply Delete ranges when rolling back add index Optimize the insert executor on duplicate key update Upgrade mysql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 26 ~ April 01, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-02-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-04-02-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 49 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support show grants for current_user(); Add manual GC back for some KV API users Support using decimal in INTERNAL  Fixed  Fix an unsigned decimal Fix a potential goroutine leak problem in copIterator Fix the AdminCheckTable bug when the column is nil and has a default value Fix type infer for the binary literal Fix a bug that lexer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 19 ~ March 25, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-26-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-26-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 35 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the average column size for histogram Support STRAIGHT_JOIN to disable join reordering Add the AdminChecksumTable command Show Region key&amp;rsquo;s record ID or index values  Fixed  Support converting json to float64 Fix incompatible behavior when modifying value from Navicat GUI Fix panic by cloning the predicates of UnionScan Fix the syntax error on set transaction isolation level serializable Fix a data race on the concurrent access of Tracker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 12 ~ March 18, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-19-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-19-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 60 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Collect query feedbacks Support admin recover index Support retry and timeout for Coprocessor streaming API Export implicit rowid and use it in CRUD  Fixed  Fix the column length when converting the column information for tinyint Add the deprecation warning for builtin function PASSWORD Add missing columns in collations_information_applicability Fix the comparison between uint and int Fix the index iterator for unique index with a null value Fix insert into t1 (select * from t) Fix a bug when performing column substitution for join Change makeJoinRowToChunk to account for virtual rows Rollback the transaction when Compile returns error  Improved  Add a unit test for distsql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 05 ~ March 11, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-12-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-12-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>TiDB 2.0 RC1 release TiDB 2.0 RC1 is released. This release has great improvement in MySQL compatibility, SQL optimization and stability.
Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 38 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support checking the consistency of an index Support decoding a column value by HTTP API Add validation for configuration Add HTTP API for settings Employ memory Tracker to track memory usage during query execution  Fixed  Fix inconsistent behavior for insert Correct the behavior of the bit aggregate function Fix a bug that index is not used in a special case Fix the field length of Boolean type Handle warnings returned from tikv/mocktikv  Improved  Set low priority for adding an index Support pseudo profiling table for compatibility Enhance decorrelation Check the password format for create user identified by password XXX Avoid the random error during Leader checking in GC Make CommitMaxBackoff configurable  Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 8 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (February 26 ~ March 04, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-03-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 27 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support stream aggregation on TiKV Support long VARCHAR Set Range and OutputCounts in Coprocessor Response for streaming API Support COMMENT = string in partition definition Add restrict and cascade in DropTable  Fixed  Set have_profiling to NO  Improved  Remove invalid intervals in building Range Resolve locks in a batch Extract the same part from DNF&amp;rsquo;s leaves Simplify the logic of HashCode Improve the performance of decoding decimal Test coverage:  Improve the test coverage in the executor package Improve the test coverage in the plan package Improve the test coverage in the distsql package  Panic recover:  Add the recover mechanism for index lookup reader workers Add the recover mechanism for union workers Add the recover panic in owner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (February 12 ~ February 25, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-02-26-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-02-26-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 27 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the select 1 order by 1 syntax  Fixed  Fix the bug in insert statements when dropping columns Fix the bug when updating the stats table  Improved  Allow golint to check context.Context in make check Do not import golang.org/x/net/context as goctx alias Move the package context to sessionctx Add the recover mechanism for join workers Add StatementsPerTransaction and TransactionDuration metrics Add keep alive metrics to figure out whether TiDB instance is down  Weekly update in TiKV and PD Last two weeks, we landed 13 PRs in the TiKV and PD repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (February 05 ~ February 11, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-02-12-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-02-12-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 67 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  CreateIndex supports the LOCK option. Add GoVersion info for tidb_version Add a session variable to show the configuration Support show stats_healthy to check if a table needs to be analyzed  Removed  Remove the useless field in jsonColumn Clean up the abandoned storage engine
  Fixed  Check the CreateTable statement charset option Fix the bug of show index printing non-public index when add index operation is not finished Treat a decimal truncate as a warning in update  Improved  Run GC workers parallelly Pass the operator label from Plan to Executor Prepare the candidate index to improve performance Use pseudo estimation when the stats of some table is outdated Ignore the error and keep GC always working Set a min count for AutoAnalyze to avoid the auto analysis of small tables Improve importer tools:  Support randDate by statistics Support generating other types of columns randomly by statistics Generate a string by statistics Support VARCHAR in set Generate the integer data by Histogram  Refine metrics in TiDB:  Rename _count to _num Unify metrics naming Add a metric for pseudo estimation Make metrics content clearer and compacter Move domain metrics and add the privilege load counter Add metrics for DDL and the server Add metrics for the DDL worker Add metrics for expensive executors and statement nodes Add metrics for stats Fix inconsistent labels for the panic counter Move DDL metrics from the ddl package to the metrics package Refine TiKV client metrics Add metrics for the DDL owner Add metrics and logs for ticlient   Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 6 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 29 ~ February 04, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-02-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-02-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 35 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the load stats command  Removed  Remove iota in DDL package to make the constant clearer  Fixed  limit and offset can be parameter markers in the prepared statement IndexOption can be a list in creating a table Fix the bug of some field length missing in creating a table Fix the bug of parsing Datetime overflow Trim leading zeros before parsing integer literal Fix the float truncate bug  Improved  Importer tools support loadStats by path Support mock table info for importer tools Let DO statement be a read only statement Improve an error handling in ddl Reduce memory allocation in buildDataSource Make Explain clearer Add the metrics package and recover Panic of Worker Refine the joinResult generator to return maxChunkSize chunk Limit lock count for ScanLock request Enhance the IndexRange calculation Refine metrics in TiDB:  Refine DistSQL metrics Add metrics for the meta package Move and refine the server metrics Add metrics for DDL syncer Update metrics for session   Weekly update in TiSpark Last week, we landed 6 PRs in the TiSpark repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 22 ~ January 28, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-29-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-29-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 28 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the importer tool Add metrics for GC failure count Add metrics for TiDB-server panic Add metrics for async secondary lock cleanup Support create time in information_schema  Removed  Remove GetSessionVars() in expression evaluation Remove varsutil package, and make Systems a private member of SessionVars  Fixed  Avoid the generation of mysql.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 15 ~ January 21, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-22-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-22-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 43 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add an interface for Chunk to count the memory usage Add a session variable to log the query string  Removed  Remove the old, never used IndexLookUpJoin  Fixed  group_concat should not modify the argument during execution Correct the unsigned pk&amp;rsquo;s behavior  Improved  Optimize the com_field_list command and make Use Database faster Improve the sort efficiency on lookupTableTask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 08 ~ January 14, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-15-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-15-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 43 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the ODBC syntax of time/date/timestamp literal Add MaxProcs and make the runtime.GOMAXPROCS parameter configurable  Fixed  Fix a bug about index join Close HashJoin goroutines as soon as possible to avoid unexpected errors fetchShowTableStatus should append an integer to the third column instead of a string Correct the behavior when RunWorker is false Refine the typeInfer of group_concat  Improved  Avoid the Children type assertion Merge IntColumnRange with NewRange Upgrade the username length limit to 32 to be compatible with MySQL 5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 01 ~ January 07, 2018)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-08-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-08-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 37 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the PACK_KEYS option in the CreateTable statement. Show job&amp;rsquo;s start time in the result of admin show ddl ....  Fixed  Fix a bug when initializing HTTP stats handler. Fix a bug when estimating row count for outdated histograms. Consider time zone for builtin functions curtime/sysdate/curdate.  Improved  Refactor Chunk.AppendRow to handle virtual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 25 ~ December 31, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-02-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2018-01-02-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 36 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the Iterator interface in Chunk.  Removed  Remove the useless aggregation function during buildQuantifierPlan.  Fixed  Flen and Decimal of TypeNewDecimal should not be -1. To pass sysbench Prepare tests, set Fields for SelectStmt in PrepareExec. Fix the case that fails to split a table. Correct the type inference of the sum and avg functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 18 ~ December 24, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-25-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-25-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 48 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the builtin aggregation function bit_or.  Removed  Remove the old JSON type. Remove the HashSemiJoin plan and executor.  Fixed  Support showing the current auto_increment id in the result of show create table. Fix a bug of NewIndexLookUpJoin&#39;s Next(). Fix the trigger condition for AutoAnalyze. Only rebuild the range when using prepared cache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 11 ~ December 17, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-18-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-18-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 46 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support SEPARATOR in the group_concat aggregate function. Support the BinaryJSON type. Add a config for the SQL parser to enable parsing syntax for window function. Support the http index MVCC interface.  Fixed  Show the index column length if necessary in show create table statement. Clear the delta info when rolling back a transaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 04 ~ December 10, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-11-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-11-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 45 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add hints to force to choose HashJoin. Provide the HTTP API of table disk usage for tidb-ctl.  Fixed  Fix a bug when updating the JSON field. Delete the auto ID key when renaming the table. Fix a bug in JoinResultGenerator. Fix a bug when backfilling the index with nil. The value of a session variable should not be modified when getting a global variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 27 ~ December 03, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-04-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-12-04-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 43 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add an option to disable Chunk. Add the schema info API of the http status server.  Removed  Remove the Align method of IndexRange.  Fixed  Set the priority for IndexLookupExecutor when reading the table. Fix the length metadata of the decimal column returned to the client. Fix the bug about auto-increment key after renaming a table from the old DB to another DB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 20 ~ November 26, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-27-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-27-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 60 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the Create View syntax. Support the PAD_CHAR_TO_FULL_LENGTH sql_mode. Support the PROXY protocol.  Fixed  Fix a bug in retry(). Fix a bug about parse duration when the fsp round overflows 60 seconds. Fix the missing index update about automatic updating for TIMESTAMP. Fix a bug when val &amp;gt; MaxInt32 in the from_unixtime argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 13 ~ November 19, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-20-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-20-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 48 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Removed  Remove redundant ResolveIndices. Remove useless error return.  Fixed  Fix the index recognized as prefix index when the column length is enlarged. Check the MaxInt64 and MinInt64 to avoid range error. Fix the estimation in betweenRowCount. Refine sql_mode no_backslash_escapes. Add deep copies for the update operation. Refine projection elimination when projection is the inner child of an outer join.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 06 ~ November 12, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-13-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-13-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB 2017-11-13
Last week, we landed 45 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support more SQL modes in TiDB:  the NO_UNSIGNED_SUB sql_mode the REAL_AS_FLOAT sql_mode the PIPES_AS_CONCAT sql_mode the high_not_precedence sql_mode the ONLY_FULL_GROUP_BY sql_mode  Parse more privilege types like RELOAD, EVENT and so on. Support part of window function AST.  Removed  Remove joinBuilder. Remove resolver.go.  Fixed  Return error instead of panic if a subquery in JOIN ON condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 30 ~ November 05, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-06-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-11-06-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 51 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Provide the command option and log the success/fail information for slow-query.  Removed  Remove the old planner. Remove xeval. Remove the localstore storage engine.  Fixed  Change the selection plan to dual plan directly if the condition is always false. Insert column char(4) with latin1 charset by incorrect padding. Remove the check of initialized auto ID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 23 ~ October 29, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-10-30-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-10-30-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 52 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the window function syntax.  Fixed  Fix an issue when the values builtin function meets the null value. Support the signed field option for the numeric type. Fix an issue of index reader. Fix an issue that the binlog client is not initialized correctly. Correct the schema type of ShowStmt. The default value length for Join should be changed for column pruning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 9 ~ October 22, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-10-23-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-10-23-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 83 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support writing slow query log into separate files. Dummy implementation for the SHOW PROFILES statement. Add metrics for automatic analyzing. Support the operation of cancel DDL jobs. Add a new http status API to get meta regions.  Removed  Remove the self field in baseBuiltinFunc completely. Remove foldable from baseBuiltinFunc.  Fixed  Fix a bug occurred in select sum(float col)*0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 25 ~ October 08, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-10-09-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-10-09-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 62 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the SyncLog Key-Value request option. Support the NotFillCache Key-Value request option. Support the combination SQL modes.  Removed  Close the aggregation pushdown by default and remove the CBO switch. Remove some useless code. Remove the usage of TypeClass completely.  Fixed  Change the like function to be case sensitive. Prepare to enforce errcheck, step 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 18 ~ September 24, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-25-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-25-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB 2017-09-25
Last week, we landed 63 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Use new expression framework by default. Support the DOT explain format. Support the syntax for EXPLAIN FORMAT = stringlit Support the TIME/TIMESTAMP literal  Removed  Remove expression/typeinfer.go entirely. Abandon the selection controller.  Fixed  Roll back the ID allocator when a transaction fails to commit. Fix the returned column length of all the SHOW statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 11 ~ September 17, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-18-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-18-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 46 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add required tables of MySQLX . Add TOML configuration file support.  Removed  Remove the performance schema instrumentation.  Fixed  Fix show create table with foreign key. Cast values only for modified columns in the update statement to avoid unnecessary check. Fix an OOM issue when analyzing table. Fix a cast (date as datetime) error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 04 ~ September 10, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-11-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-11-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 49 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the column size limit when creating table. Add the syntax for admin show ddl jobs. SSL/TLS support.  Fixed  Fix an ORDER BY bug. Add entry limit for transactions when doing DDL job. Fix a bug during the limit operator pushdown. Check the default value of the column option in the CREATE TABLE statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 28 ~ September 03, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-04-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-09-04-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 42 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add JSON into builtin if function.  Fixed  Fix bugs when doing natural JOIN or JOIN with using clause. Check whether date is zero and returns error when casting int as the time type. Support date time format when parse duration. Fix the issue that SHOW CREATE TABLE COMMENT is not escaped and the issue that FieldType.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 21 ~ August 27, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-28-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-28-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 55 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the &amp;lsquo;SHOW PLUGINS&amp;rsquo; syntax with dummy implementation. Add a system variable to split to-be-deleted data into batches autmatically. Add the date literal. Add the framework of the X protocol, and commond line arguments.  Fixed  Fix a panic when the set statement meets a subquery. Set charset and collation for the union&amp;rsquo;s result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 14 ~ August 20, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-21-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-21-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 57 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the version information in diagnostic messages. Add the Close() method to RawKVClient. Add JSON in fieldTypeMergeRules. Add support to MySQL connector 6.06. Add Git branch name in tidb_version() and the starting log. Add the auto analyze feature for tables.  Fixed  DDL uses the correct method to check whether the context is done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 07 ~ August 13, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-14-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-14-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 78 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Enable pushing down the following operations to TiKV.  the JSON function ifnull minus and multiply  Use the Delete-in-Range feature to speed up the Drop Database/Table/Index operations. Support prioritizing statements.  Fixed  Fix the TimeDiff compatibility issue. Consider charset in Right/Left/Substr. Do not record metrics when running intenal SQL. Fix potential issue of schema validation check.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 31 ~ August 06, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-07-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-08-07-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 54 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support natural join. Add a switch for enabling cost-based optimizor. Assign low priority for SQL with full table scan and high priority for SQL with point get. Support \N which is the shotcut of null. Support TIMESTAMP in the get_format function. Add a flag to enable TCP keep-alive. Support DISTINCTROW.  Fixed  Truncate the trailing spaces for &amp;ldquo;CHAR[(M)]&amp;rdquo; types Fix float point parsing with leading dot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 24 ~ July 30, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-31-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-31-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 50 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add a debugging tool for transaction inspection. Support two JSON syntactic sugars. Support renaming multiple tables in a single statement.  Fixed  Fix a bug in the update statement when doing the alter table after statement. Fix signed integer overflow in the minus unary scalar function. Fix the content in the information_schema for unsigned columns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 17 ~ July 23, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-24-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-24-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 60 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add a tidb_version function to get the tidb-server version information. Support the READ COMMITTED isolation level. Support the ENCLOSED BY clause in the Load Data statement. Support creating index using type and comment.  Fixed  Fix a bug when in json_unquote. Fix field name with comment. Fix the wrong offset when using the Primary Key column as the handle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 10 ~ July 16, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-17-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-17-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 51 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support setting variables with ON and OFF. Support show stats_histgrams and show stats_buckets for debugging. Support the Scan API for the raw KV interface. Support the Show Charset statement. Support user name without quotes such as root@127.0.0.1.  Fixed  Fix a bug when explicitly inserting the null value into columns with the timestamp type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 26 ~ July 02, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-04-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-07-04-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 33 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support priority options in the select statement. Add the GetOwnerID interface in OwnerManager. Add some columns in mysql.db: Make it compatible with MySQL. Add the IsolationLevel option in the coprocessor request to TiKV. Add the priority option in Key-Value request to TiKV. Support the RenameTable statement without the To keyword.  Fixed  Fix a bug in the update statement like update T set a = 8, b = a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 19 ~ June 25, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-26-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-26-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 35 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  JSON type:  Tiny cleanup. Fix a bug in JSON path_expr. Fix a bug in unquote. Make json_unquote compatiable with MySQL Code cleanup.   Fixed  Fix failed test cases on the ppc64le platform Fix a bug when naming table with the auto_increment column. Use UTC time to compose index key for timestamp column.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 12 ~ June 18, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-20-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-20-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 30 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Refactor the optimizer:  Refactor ranger/statistic: calculate the range and row count of non pk column.  JSON type:  Support generated column:](https://github.com/pingcap/tidb/pull/3431) Support the JSON type in the cast expression.  Generated column:  Support basic generated column. Prevent modifying generated column. Add GeneratedExpr in ColumnInfo.  Support using clause in join statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (June 06 ~ June 11, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-12-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-12-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 52 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Refactor the optimizer:
 Add an statsProfile interface to propagate statistic information among plans. Implement the statsProfile interface for the Join plan.  JSON type:
 Suport json_set, json_insert, json_replace and json_merge. Support the JSON type in the cast expression.  Use gRPC between TiDB and TiKV.
 Refactor the Analyze executor.
 Add the SubDuration function in util package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 22 ~ June 05, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-06-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 53 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support using After and First to specify column position in the Alter Table Statement.
 Support the password builtin function.
 Support the inet6_ntoa builtin function.
 Support the Extract and Unquote function for Json.
 Support json_{set/insert/replace} and json_merge for Json.
 Support batched Index Lookup Join.
  Fixed  Fix a goroutine leak problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 15 ~ May 21, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-22-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-22-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 31 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Use etcd to elect DDL job leader.
 Support Load Data with specified column list.
 Add the following builtin functions:
 umcompress and uncompressdlength convert_tz period-diff  Support the Json type and Json data encoding/decoding.
 Add a Jenkins CI in Pull Request.
 Add the EvalDuration and EvalTime interface for expressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 08 ~ May 14, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-15-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-15-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 28 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add builtin function uncompress and uncompressdlength, convert_tz, period-diff
 Fill data into information_schema.key_column_usage.
 Add Open interface for Executor.
 Show warnings for Load Data statement.
 Support Json type and functions in parser.
 Support top-n operator in new planner.
  Fixed  Consider session variable time_zone for timestamp datum.
 Fix data race problem in IndexLookup Executor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (May 01 ~ May 07, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-08-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-08-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 33 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add builtin function is_ipv4_mapped, makedate, utc_time
 Enable privilege checking by default. You could also disable privilege checking through --privilege=false.
 Support Analyze Index statement: after adding an index, we could run this statement to analyze the newly added index.
 Add Trigger_priv column in mysql.user system table.
 Add coveralls in CI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 24 ~ April 30, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-02-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-05-02-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 49 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add builtin function truncate, makedate, utc_time
 Add pre-commit hook.
 Add a plan for Analyze.
 Add a check list about the things that contributors should think about before sending a PR.
 Support ENGINE option with partition option in table definition.
 Add code review guide.
  Fixed  Fix bug in converting string to hex/bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (April 10 ~ April 16, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-04-17-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-04-17-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 26 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Update etcd client in vendor.
 Add builtin function time-to-sec
 Add definition for builtin functions: bit_count, to_base64, right
  Fixed  Fix the error message for data overflow.
 Fix a panic.
 Fix a bug in top-n pushdown.
 Fix a data race bug in session context.
 Fix a bug in name resolver for GroupBy clause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 27 ~ April 09, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-04-10-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-04-10-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 74 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support Index Nest Lookup Join operator.#2834, #2945
 Add many builtin functions: quote, is_ipv4, compress, inet_aton, format, bin, random-bytes, sin, inet_ntoa, cos, from_base64, tan, cot, to_days, timestampadd
 Check privileges for show databases/tables statement.
 Calculate distinct information in statistic module.#2947, #2966
 Add a switcher to split large inset transaction into multiple small transactions automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 20 ~ March 26, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-27-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-27-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 40 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support Sort Merge Join operator.
 Add many builtin functions: degree, insert, instr, any_value, elt, uuid, ord, sin, inet_ntoa, maketime, sha2, quarter
 Add a command line flag to start TiDB without authentication function.
 Support use special comment /*+ */ for optimizer hint.
 Make index serial scan concurrency configurable with system variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 13 ~ March 19, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-20-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-20-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 33 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add system table mysql.stats_meta: used for storing statistic information.
 Add a Restful API to get region info from pd.
 Add a system variable to control the behavior of unfolding subquery in in expression.
 Add many builtin functions: acos, asin, atan, make_set, oct, pi, lpad, radians, exp, ip_v6
  Fixed  Check truncated UTF8 string when casting value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (March 06 ~ March 12, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-13-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-13-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 30 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add context in exector: prepare for canceling execution.
 Support the KILL statement.
 Support string literal with in the national character set N&#39;literal&#39;.
 Check privilege when running create user statement.
 Add a session variable to prevent eager aggregation.
  Fixed  Clean up pending task when close executor: fix memory leak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (February 27 ~ March 05, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-06-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-03-06-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 21 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add metrics for related region count for a transaction.
 Record sql_mode in session context.
 Support Show Processlist.
 Add an empty Triggers table in information_schema database.
 Support ANSI_QUOTES sql_mode in parser.
 Support use wildcard as user hostname in grant statement.
 Support the MD5 builtin function.
 Support the SHA/SHA1 builtin function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (February 19 ~ February 26, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-02-27-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-02-27-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 39 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support Revoke statement.
 Add rules in parser and empty implementation for unsupported builtin functions: #2667, #2677, #2679
 Support wildcard chars in username or host in Grant statement.
 Add a context arggument for distsql/kv interface: We will use the context to cancel running jobs.
 Support Create Table ... Like statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (February 06 ~ February 12, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-02-13-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-02-13-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 25 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support basic privilege framework: #2423, #2557, #2603, #2607,
 Support ALTER [COLUMN] col_name SET DEFAULT statement.
 Validate column default value when creating table.
 Support ALTER TABLE ... DROP DEFAULT statement.
 Support changing default value and comment in alter table statement.
  Fixed  Fix build on i386.
 Fix output format of prometheus interval log.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 23 ~ February 05, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-02-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-02-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 43 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support information_schema.table_constraints.
 Support the UTC_TIMESTAMP builtin function
 Increase transaction entry count limit.
 Add logs for expensive query and big transaction: 2536, 2545, 2546
  Fixed  Fix GC lifetime metrics.
 Fix primary key name parsing.
 Fix a bug of left outer semi join.
 Fix a bug of exists sub query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 09 ~ January 22, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-01-24-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-01-24-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last two weeks, we landed 87 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support statistic on index data
 Support file sort operator
 Add key prefix length limitation on index
 Support the TIMESTAMPDIFF built-in function.
 Support the CONV built-in function.
 Support the SUBSTR built-in function.
 Support the SIGN built-in function.
 Support the FROM_DAYS built-in function.
 Support the FIELD built-in function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (January 02 ~ January 08, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-01-08-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-01-08-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 38 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add nested loop join.
 Support the UNIX_TIMESTAMP built-in function.
 Support the INTERVAL built-in function.
 Support the FIND_IN_SET built-in function.
 Support the DATEDIFF built-in function.
 Enable pushing down IF expr to TiKV coprocessor
  Fixed  In prepared statement, limit and offset could be parameter marker.
 When creating table, index option could be a list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 26 ~ January 01, 2017)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-01-01-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2017-01-01-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 28 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the CHAR_LENGTH built-in function.
 Support the CRC32 built-in function.
 Support the LEAST built-in function.
  Fixed  Fix a bug in Add Column with invalid default value.
 Fix a bug about parsing string to float.
 Fix a bug when using int and uint as join key.
 Fix a bug in MySQL Protocol layer about prepared statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 19 ~ December 25, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-26-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-26-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>New Release TiDB RC1 is released!
Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 34 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the RPAD built-in function..
 Support the show keys from table from database statement.
  Fixed  Retry infinite times if the commit primary key times out.
 Do not push aggregation down to the memory tables.
 Fix a bug about the alter table statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 12 ~ December 18, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-19-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-19-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 32 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Add the FlagIgnoreTruncate/FlagTruncateAsWarning flag to control the behavior of truncated errors.
 Add the prompt text flag.
 Add the rawkv metrics to profile the rawkv API performance.
 Add a comparable varint encoding/decoding method to make encoded data smaller.
 Support the timediff built-in function.
 Support the following built-in functions: ln(), log(), log2(), log10().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (December 05 ~ December 11, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-12-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-12-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 41 PRs in the TiDB repositories.
Added  Support the built-in function: str_to_date. 
 Support built-in function schema().
 Support pushing the case-when expression to TiKV.
 Support changing the type and name of a column.
 Add the `session_variablesandplugins` of memory table to infoschema.
 Make the union all operator run parallelly.
 Support explaining the union statement.
  Fixed  A bug that causes infinite loop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 28 ~ December 04, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-12-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 48 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 6 PRs in the TiDB docs repositories.
Added  Support the built-in function: str_to_date. 
 Refactor the time structure: Introduce a TimeInternal interface to replace the go time representation.
 Add the raw Key-Value API  and make TiKV a raw Key-Value engine.
 Add a bench tool for the raw Key-Value API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 21 ~ November 27, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-28-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-28-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 44 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 3 PRs in the TiDB docs repositories.
Added  Support creating anonymous index.
 Add the mailing list for TiDB users.
 Support the show events syntax.
  Fixed  Enlarge the Time To Live (TTL)for large transactions.
 Parse float literal using the decimal parser.
 Prevent panic for malformed packets.
 Fix the behavior in the aggregate operator: for the select a, c from t groupby t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 14 ~ November 20, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-21-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-21-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update in TiDB Last week, we landed 30 PRs in the TiDB repositories, 3 PRs in the TiDB docs repositories.
Added  Add a session variable to skip unique constraint check: This could be used when migrating data.
 More metrics for statement counter.
  Fixed  Use reserved keywords as the table/column name.
 Add missing comments in the show table status result.
 Fix a bug that gets duplicate auto_inc ID after truncating table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (November 07 ~ November 13, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-14-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-14-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Last week, we landed 25 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 5 PRs in the TiDB docs repositories.
Weekly update in TiDB Added  Support the Alter table modify column statement.
 Support the Drop view statement: parsed but ignored.
 Add metrics for the transaction size.
 A tool for testing the SQL performance.
  Fixed  A bug in the show create table statement.
 A few bugs in optimizer: #1962, #1963, #1966, #1975, #1977.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 31 ~ November 06, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-07-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-11-07-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (October 31 ~ November 06, 2016) Last week, we landed 42 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 29 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
New release TiDB Beta 4 Weekly update in TiDB Added  The aggregation info to the explain statement.
 Support the show processlist syntax. TiDB supports mydumper now.
 Support the show create database statement.
 Support the buildin function from_unixtime.
 Push down the aggregation operator to the position before join.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 24 ~ October 30, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-10-31-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-10-31-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (October 24 ~ October 30, 2016) Last week, we landed 24 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 28 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Support coalesce/case when pushing down on local storage
 Support showing indexes in the table syntax.
 Split eval.go into some smaller files to make code cleaner.
 Fix a bug about truncating data.
 Fix the mysql version number format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 17 ~ October 23, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-10-24-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-10-24-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (October 17 ~ October 23, 2016) Last week, we landed 30 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 26 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Set the concurrency for the SQL executor using the Set statement
 Convert the Limit+Sort operator to the TopN operator on local storage
 Fix the gotouinue leak problem
 Support the logic/bitwise operator on local storage
 Support creating user without password</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (October 01 ~ October 16, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-10-17-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-10-17-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (October 01 ~ October 16, 2016) Last week, we landed 27 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 32 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Support projection elimination so that the executor can run faster when it is not necessary to have a projection layer.
 Write DDL binlog to file.
 Convert sort and limit to top-n in the query planning phrase.
 Support reading history data even if the schema changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 26 ~ September 30, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-30-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-30-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (September 26 ~ September 30, 2016) Last week, we landed 17 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 13 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Make the GC alive time configurable so that users can keep the deleted data as long as they want. Add the metrics for all kinds of statements to provide more information for insights. Improve the kv package test coverage. Record the processed row count during DDL so that users can track the progress of DDL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 19 ~ September 25, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-26-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-26-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (September 19 ~ September 25, 2016) Last week, we landed 20 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 24 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Support DML binlog. Support reading the history data. Add more metrics to distsql, DDL, and store. Replace the vendor tool with glide. Improve test coverage. Code cleanup. Improve the test code by splitting a big test file into smaller files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 12 ~ September 18, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-19-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-19-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (September 12 ~ September 18, 2016) Last week, we landed 18 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 26 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Add the Prometheus metrics and support push. Support the streaming aggregation operator. Rename xapi to distsql to improve readability. Add git hash to the TiDB server status API. Improve test coverage in the abstract syntax tree (AST). Enable the division operator for the distributed SQL statements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (September 05 ~ September 11, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-12-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-12-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (September 05 ~ September 11, 2016) Last week, we landed 20 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 32 PRs in the TiKV repositories..
Notable changes to TiDB  Support mydumper Use MySQL standard error code in the DDL execution results Use heap sort operator to handle the statements with Limit and Orderby Add support for the CLIENT_CONNECT_ATTRS Add the constant propagation support to the SQL optimizer Optimize the index scan executor to improve the performance Optimize the distributed SQL API protocol to improve the performance Fix several bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 29 ~ September 04, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-09-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (August 29 ~ September 04, 2016) Last week, we landed 29 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 24 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Support the unhex and the ceiling/ceil functions Improve the Parser to handle \r\n. Solve the potential concurrency issues Support Load Data Use the Pipeline model to filter data through indexes to improve the performance Improve the code to reduce memory allocation and improve the performance Fix several bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 22 ~ August 28, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-29-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-29-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (August 22 ~ August 28, 2016) Last week, we landed 26 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 26 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Support the MySQL SetOption Command and Multiple Statements. Support filter push-down for the Time/Decimal type. Support converting OuterJoin to InnerJoin by using Null Reject. Support multiple-thread Hash Join. Support Garbage Collector. Optimize the code to improve the Performance. Fix several bugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 13 ~ August 21, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-22-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-22-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (August 13 ~ August 21, 2016) Last week, we landed 26 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 15 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Upgrade the query optimizer. Upgrade the lexer. Replace golang protobuf with gogo protobuf. Optimize the distributed executor. Repair the Time and Decimal types to improve the compatibility with MySQL. Support the Set names binary statement. Support Covering Index. Optimize the table scanning when the condition is false constant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (August 05 ~ August 12, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-12-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-12-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (August 05 ~ August 12, 2016) Last week, we landed 20 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 11 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Rewrite Lexer and improve the speed of parsing SQL texts by 40%. Add a command line flag for log output file and rotate log files regularly. Optimize the 2 phase commit process and adopt faster methods to clear locks. Optimize the execution speed of the Insert On Duplicate Update statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 30 ~ August 05, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-05-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-08-05-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (July 30 ~ August 05, 2016) Last week, we landed 28 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 32 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Add support for constant folding in the SQL optimizer. Optimize the query speed of the secondary index. In certain scenarios, only the data in the index needs to be read. Use dynamic programing to decide the join path for multiple tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 23 ~ July 29, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-07-29-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-07-29-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (July 23 ~ July 29, 2016) Last week, we landed 27 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 34 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Support cost based query optimization. Set the new query optimizer as default to improve the speed of complex queries. Meanwhile, a start-up parameter is provided to switch to the old query optimizer. Use Varint to encode the Column Value with integer type and Column ID, which saves storage space significantly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly update (July 17 ~ July 22, 2016)</title>
      <link>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-07-23-tidb-weekly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pingcap.com/weekly/2016-07-23-tidb-weekly/</guid>
      <description>Weekly update (July 17 ~ July 22, 2016) Last week, we landed 22 PRs in the TiDB repositories and 15 PRs in the TiKV repositories.
Notable changes to TiDB  Refactor the query optimizer to imporve the query efficiency for Join and SubQuery Add distributed SQL support for aggregate functions Improve the stability of the TiDB service Refactor the Decimal codes to improve the compatibility with MySQL Optimize the TiDB compatibility and performance for Zabbix Enhance the performance and the Sysbench result is improved significantly  Notable changes to TiKV  Add asynchronous scheduler support for higher throughput and better performance, see Benchmark.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>